Guide to the Louis Gottschalk Papers [ca. 1927]-1975
University of Chicago Library
- Series VIII: Notes
  - 1814-1816 (Box 93)
  - 1817-1823 (Box 94)
  - January 1824-September 1824 (Box 95)
  - October 1824-June 1825 (Box 96)
  - July 1825-1827 (Box 97)
  - 1828-June 1830 (Box 98)
  - July 1830-December 1830 (Box 99)
  - January 1831-April 1832 (Box 100)
  - May 1832-After Lafayette's death (Box 101)
  - "Negligibles" 1789-1790 (Box 102)
  - "Negligibles" 1790 (Box 103)
  - Uncertain dates and no dates. (Box 104)
  - New Fiches (since 1972) (Box 105)
- Series IX: Note Cards
  - Bibliographies; A-B (Box 106)
  - Bibliographies; A-B.C-E (Box 107)
  - Bibliographies; A-B.F-J (Box 108)
  - Bibliographies; A-B.K-L (Box 109)
  - Bibliographies; A-B.M-O (Box 110)
  - Bibliographies; A-B.O-S (Box 111)
  - Bibliographies; A-B.S-Z (Box 112)
  - Undergraduate Lectures (Box 113)
  - Philosophas (Box 114)
  - French Revolution 1787-1792 (Box 115)
  - French Revolution 1792-1799 (Box 116)
  - Jean Paul Marat (Box 117)
  - Napoleon (Box 118)
  - Franco-American Relations (Box 119)
  - Seminar and Methods Courses (Box 120)
  - Miscellaneous Notes and Lectures (Box 121)
  - Shelf list I (Box 122)
  - Shelf list II (Box 123)
- Series X: Microfilm
  - 1789 and 1792 and Miscellaneous, Swan Discourse La Rochfoucauld Correspondence Regulation of "Delits et peines" for Paris National Guard, 1789 Regulation of "Usage of arms" for the Paris National Guard, 1789 Lettre au LaFayette à la Paris National Guard New conspiration Memoire sur la formation d'une compagnie de grenadiers Lettre de M. Alexander D'Aumont National Guard Regulations, 1789 Val Rachert (probably DeWitt papers) B.M. (Additional Mss.) Collection of S.W.J.-to Lecuer, to Sapey. Mickewreg. George Washington, 1781, 3 letters Archives of ? Seine and Dagrange Cabinet Gardner Collection Lee numeros purisieurs...par M.D....1788 Voyage autour des galeries Sillery Discours, sur les rouétés populaires, et un la letter de Lafayette; and Interrogatoire de M....Lafayette Proces verbal des séances de L'Assemblée de l'ordence de la Noblesse de la Séné chaussie d'Amuergue 1789 "Lee Bassesses de l'arme bleu et condiute ..." From John Gouph, 24 August 1840 Letter from Beranger to Lafayette, 26 July 1801 Versailles, Road to and plan of chateau from Batifol Article (Box 124, Folder 1)
  - Indiana University, Gardner-Ball Collection, Lafayette to Louis XVIII (1783); Correspondence 1783-1812 Correspondence 1814-1825 Correspondence 1814-1825 1825-1827 Correspondence 1814-1825 1828-1830 Correspondence 1814-1825 1830-1832 Correspondence 1814-1825 1833-n.d. (Box 125, Folder 1)
  - Indiana University, Gardner-Ball Collection, Correspondence n.d.-1804 Correspondence n.d.-1804 1826-1832 Correspondence n.d.-1804 1803-1833 Correspondence n.d.-1804 1828-n.d. Correspondence n.d.-1804 1822-1849 Correspondence n.d.-1804 Compte Rendu to Printed Matter Compte Rendu-par M.J.M. (Box 126, Folder 1)
  - Miscellaneous, New York Historical Society Roll Number 1 (Letters from Lafayette to George Washington) Quatorze juillet 1790, ou la Fédération de la lidue contre Louis XVI. Formation Garde Nationale- Organization and pay scales for Officers, September 1789 Two Cornell University Film Reels Sparks Mss. Number 32 Sparks Mss. Number 86 Sparks Mss. Number 87 Sparks Mss. Number 88 Sparks Mss. Number 89 (Box 127, Folder 1)
  - Library of Congress Microfilms, Rochambeau Papers Miscellaneous Letters Washington Papers PCC 156 (11 Feb. 1786 to 28 April 1788) Henley Smith Papers PCC and Treasury Papers Miscellaneous Manuscripts Letters 1791 PCC 156 Washington Papers (Feb. 23, 1781 to Dec. 4, 1782) Washington Papers (Feb. 23, 1781 to Dec. 4, 1782). (28 May 1788 to 18 Jan. 1830) Washington Papers (Feb. 23, 1781 to Dec. 4, 1782). (30 July 1781 to 30 March 1782) (Box 128, Folder 1)
  - 1789 and After, Letter; Lafayette to Louis XVI, February 28, 1890 Reel; a) Papers of Society of the Cincinnati; b) PCC number 137, Calonne-Lafayette Correspondence; c) George Washington Papers; d) PCC 156 Jay letters Photographic Plates-Lafayette to Howe, April 16, 1832 University of Virginia-Alderman Library-Lafayette Inventory from Paris Nationale Archives Lafayette Letters McHenry Letters Letter of Adrieine and celebration, July 4, 1797 Mme. Bernon's Collection (Letter to Garnier-Pages) Outline of Volume 4 SCHM Selections from Diplomatic Dispatches (black reel) Comité Militaire fiched 1792 Journal General de L'Europe Unidentified Film from Austrian State Archives (Box 129, Folder 1)
  - Library of Congress and Miscellaneous, PCC 156 (26 July 1781 to 6 Sept. 1785) Letters to Short, Murray and Morse Lafayette and Nichola Fish (1825 to 1831 typescripts) Lafayette and the Revolution, Mss. Chapters 1 to 19, First Draft) Olavarria Letters in Jackson Collection, Lafayette's Honorary Degree Miscellaneous Film Observations du Gen. Lafayette Fabvier Papers L'Indicateur, Un Journal des causes et des effets "Le Curieux," Letters from Lafayette to Marborg Addition to the Library of Congress Films Washington Papers. Hamilton Papers. Miscellaneous Call Numbers. (Box 130, Folder 1)
- Series XI: Annotated Books
  - Jean Paul Marat; A Study in Radicalism. New York; Greenberg, Publisher, Inc., 1927 (Box 131)
  - The Use of Personal Documents in History, Anthropology, and Sociology. ("Social Science Research Council Bulletin," No. 53.) New York; Social Science Research Council, 1945. (Box 131)
  - Lafayette Joins the American Army. Chicago; The University of Chicago Press, 1937. (Box 131)
  - Lafayette and the Close of the American Revolution. Chicago; The University of Chicago Press, 1942, (with Clyde Kluckhohn and Robert Angell). (Box 131)
  - Lafayette between the American and the French Revolution (1783-1789). Chicago; The University of Chicago Press, 1950 (Box 131)
  - Lafayette Comes to America, Chicago; The University of Chicago Press, 1935 (Box 131)
  - The Life of Jean Paul Marat. Girard, Kansas; Haldeman-Julius Co., 1923. (Box 131)
  - The Ancient Regime (France Before the Revolution). Girard, Kansas; Haldeman-Julius Co., 1924 (Box 131)
  - The Fall of Louis XVI. Girard, Kansas; Haldeman-Julius Co., 1924 (Box 131)
  - The First French Republic. Girard, Kansas; Haldeman-Julius Co., 1924 (Box 131)
  - The Conculate of Napoleon Bonaparte. Girard, Kansas; Haldeman-Julius Co., 1925 (Box 131)
  - The Empire of Napoleon. Girard, Kansas; Haldeman-Julius Co., 1925 (Box 131)
  - Restoration and Reaction in France, 1814-1815, Girard, Kansas; Haldeman-Julius Co., 1925 (Box 131)
  - (with Donald Lach). Europe and the Modern World. 2 vols. Chicago; Scott, Foresman, and Company, 1951, 1954 (Box 132)
- Series XII: Addenda; Tape Transcripts
  - Letter from Michael T. Ryan to Leo Shelburt (Box 133, Folder 1)
  - Tape Transcription, first conversation, 30 March 1973 (Box 133, Folder 2)
  - Tape Transcription, second conversation, April 1973 (Box 133, Folder 3)
  - Tape Transcription, second conversation, April 1973 (Box 133, Folder 4)
  - Tape Transcription, third conversation, 30 May 1973 (Box 133, Folder 5)
  - Tape Transcription, fourth conversation, 19 Feb 1974 (Box 133, Folder 6)
  - Tape Transcription, fifth conversation, March 1974 (Box 133, Folder 7)
  - Tape Transcription, original manuscript, 30 March 1973 (Box 133, Folder 8)